# **SUMMARY**

Highly adaptable and resourceful analytics professional with 5 years of experience focused on building custom analytics solutions and providing actionable insights. I am well-versed in Python, R, and SQL; always eager to learn more about underlying business processes in order to create meaningful solutions; and ...

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Mathematical Statistics, Minor in Economics Ohio University, Athens OH

Overall G.P.A: 3.82 / 4.00 Magna Cum Laude

Major G.P.A: 3.98 / 4.00 \*Diploma Conferred on Dec 10th, 2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## ROOT INSURANCE

Columbus OH

Feb 2019 - Current Oct 2021 - Current

## Data Analyst II - LTV Analytics

Technology Used: SQL, R, Tableau, Mode Analytics, git

• Provide analytics support for outside business requests on customer lifetime value related (LTV) metrics, and in the midst of designing a suite of executive-facing dashboards that provide insight into the validity and stability of our model produced LTV metrics.

## Software Engineer I, II - Data Science Engineering

Mar 2020 - Sept 2021

Technology Used: Python, AWS, Docker, git, BuildKite, Terraform

- Provided continued support for the customer lifetime value prediction process, and helped create internal packages and templates for data scientists for easier machine learning model deployment in AWS SageMaker.
- Worked on developing SageMaker Endpoint APIs and serverless infrastructure to transition the scoring of users' telematics scores out of a Ruby on Rails app.

## Senior Product Analyst - Mobile App Conversion

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

Technology Used: R, SQL, Python, AWS, Docker, git, Tableau

- Set up the initial daily customer lifetime value prediction process using AWS SageMaker, Lambda, and an internal data extraction tool. These results, while originally for the growth marketing team, became a staple in the company's overall decision making process.
- Led the analysis for several meaningful A/B tests in the mobile app experience, including: the efficacy of providing easy access to phone

support during key points in the customer journey, and the improvement to several business metrics by allowing customer choice to affect their product experience.

• Worked to standardize the analysis of conversion A/B tests by creating an R package that provided analysts an abstraction for conducting a Bayesian analysis and producing a standardized report of results.

#### AMERICAN ELECTRIC POWER

Columbus OH

Jan 2017 - Feb 2019

#### **CHARGE Solutions Consultant**

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

Technology Used: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SmartSheet

• Worked closely with various business units on micro-projects to increase efficiency in their workflows by incorporating SmartSheet while training in technologies for both web and mobile app development.

#### Associated Data Scientist

Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

Technology Used: Python, R, Oracle, Linux, Docker, git

- Created a daily statistical process for a quality control team that automated
  the prediction and cataloguing of potential errors in transmission data for
  600 large commercial customers. Additionally created a dashboard with
  Oracle APEX that provided the team with a workflow to view and post
  notes about the predictions.
- Developed a data analysis tool and discrete-event simulation program that provided the ability to analyze the expected annualized costs for various predictive maintenance inspection regimens of the Amos power plant.
- Co-led an internal monthly meet-up around the uses of Python and R for analytics, where we typically had between 5 and 10 people attend each month.